<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Enterprise | Knowledge Mining]]></title>
  <link href="http://murraju.github.io/blog/categories/enterprise/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://murraju.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-08T12:42:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://murraju.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Murali Raju]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[murali.raju@appliv.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speed and Agility are not enough for Enterprises]]></title>
    <link href="http://murraju.github.io/blog/2014/06/08/speed-and-agility-are-not-enough-for-enterprises/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-08T10:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://murraju.github.io/blog/2014/06/08/speed-and-agility-are-not-enough-for-enterprises</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most Open Source implementations of Web-Scale Architectures focus on Speed and Agility as the Foundational Layer.
On the contrary, Enterprises build from a Foundational Layer of Compliance, Policy, Governance, Security and resistance
to change. So, what does it take Open Source Web-Scale Architectures to succeed in an Enterprise?</p>

<p>After many years of evangelism, strategy planning, design, build and operating large-scale infrastructures powered by Open Source,
I wanted to share my thoughts.</p>

<h2>Enterprise Adoption</h2>

<ol>
<li>Open Source projects need to delicately balance stability with features. Stability trumps features in most Enterprises.</li>
<li>Security, Compliance, Policy, Governance, Monitoring should be part of the core and not an afterthought.</li>
<li>Migration of workloads should be transparent as much as possible to reuse existing investment &ndash; at least for the near term.</li>
</ol>


<p>All of the above are not easy to achieve for various reasons. Open Source is not about just throwing the code out there. Diplomacy, Community
and Ecosystem development determine success or adoption rate.</p>

<p>From another point of view, the above also opens up a startup ecosystem to augment gaps or even progressive incumbents to shape the market.</p>

<p>Classical models include:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open Core with closed Management Layer as &ldquo;Conveninent Differentiator&rdquo;. Stability is generally achieved by forking with upstream-push
to the Open Core. Security, Compliance, Governance, Policy Management, Monitoring and Migration capabilities are rolled into the closed Management Layer.</li>
<li>Pure-Play models focus on packaging stable branches with Open Source Add-ons. Support provided either as Managed Services or Support Agreements.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Build or Buy?</h2>

<p>Enterprises are faced with a dilemma when it comes to Open Source &ndash; do I build everything myself or leverage vendors on either #1 or #2 models?</p>

<p>I have seen strategies &ldquo;We will build everything ourselves, since it is Open Source and want to avoid vendor-lockin&rdquo;. This may seem ideal at the beginning and great on
power points. However, without truly understanding what it takes &ndash; cost, cultural and organizational changes required and overall launching a product organization within the
Enterprise &ndash; this almost 100% set for failure.</p>

<h2>A Potential Solution</h2>

<p>A potential solution would be to leverage both. Organization Inertia &ndash; Organizational and Cultural changes will take the longest time and therefore, developing a roadmap that encompasses a vendor
strategy to bootstrap and in parellel, building in-house talent would perhaps be the best strategy. In order to mitigate risks on attrition, a services and staff aug vendor strategy
is key.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
